<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Victory in Jesus]]></title><description><![CDATA[We can have victory because Our Lord and Savior conquered Sin and Death!]]></description><link>http://thevictoryisyours.com/</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 04:42:32 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Trust God and Don't worry]]></title><description><![CDATA[Trust is hard thing to do for some people. When you worry you are not trusting God. God loves you and wants you to trust in him. Will you?]]></description><link>http://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/trusting-god-and-not-worrying</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/trusting-god-and-not-worrying</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Trust is hard thing to do for some people. When you worry you are not trusting God. God loves you and wants you to trust in him. Will you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust begins with being a believer. Do you believe in Jesus? If you do that means you have already put your faith into Jesus Christ. So you have established a relationship of trust. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard part is to keep that trust in all seasons of your life. In life you will go through many trials. Trials come into your life to build up your faith and trust. Trials bring you closer to God. How do you become closer? It starts by trusting in God. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has a plan for you. He has promised this to us in Jeremiah 29:11. He has plans for us. For us to have a future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get it sometimes its hard to have trust when you can’t see every step of the way. However, always remember. We walk by faith and not by sight. So what can we do? We need to pray constantly. Let our prayers be known to God. Do not worry about anything. Instead pray about everything and make your requests be known to God. Who will answer them according to His will.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why it's Good to be Content]]></title><description><![CDATA[The passage of Matthew 4 is one of the greatest inspirational messages. It's a clear example of how we can overcome any trial in life.]]></description><link>http://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/why-we-should-be-content</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/why-we-should-be-content</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Being happy is all about perspective. Yes you can choose happiness. Happiness is a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is one of the biggest reasons of being happy? It’s when we focus on what we don’t have. Instead of being grateful for the things you do have. Remember everything good in your life comes from God. It’s up to God how and when he blesses us. So once you change your perspective you will see how blessed you really are. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally remember it’s always best to be humble. God resists the proud and gives grace to the humble.                           &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[We can have Victory with Jesus Christ]]></title><description><![CDATA[The passage of Matthew 4 is one of the greatest inspirational messages. It's a clear example of how we can overcome any trial in life.]]></description><link>http://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/we-can-have-victory-with-christ</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/we-can-have-victory-with-christ</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The passage of Matthew 4 is one of the greatest inspirational messages. It’s a clear example of how we can overcome any trial in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we do this? My easiest answer is to keep your eyes on Jesus. Think about what happend to Peter when he took his eyes off Jesus. The minute he started to look at the waves he began to drown. This is a classic example of what happens when we take our eyes off Jesus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said &lt;blockquote&gt;
“These things I have spoken to you, that in Me you may have peace. In the world you [f]will have tribulation; but be of good cheer, I have overcome the world.” - John 16:33 &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the most important thing to remember our Lord and Savior Jesus Chrsit overame sin and death. There is nothing Jesus can’t overcome and we have Jesus on our side. How great is that!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this passage of scripture Jesus sets the exmaple on how to deal with temptation. Jesus is tempted three times by Satan in the desert. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Jesus responds? He responds by using the Sword of the Spirit. This is the only weapon we need to defeat the enemy. It is our offensive and our defense as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our enemy the devil prowls around like a roaring lion looking for someone to devour(1 Peter 5:8). He is very manipulative. That is why it’s so important to know the word of God. Look at how in verse 6 Satan actually tried to twist the truth and use it against Jesus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus responded and said it is written you should not temp the Lord your God. By knowing and using the Word of God as a weapon. The enemy can’t condemn us because we have the truth. The Word of God! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember what it says in Romans 8:1.
&lt;q&gt;There is therefore now no condemnation to them which are in Christ Jesus, who walk not after the flesh, but after the Spirit.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>