<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Victory in Jesus]]></title><description><![CDATA[We can have victory because Our Lord and Savior conquered Sin and Death!]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com/</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 23:49:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Blessings from the Cross]]></title><description><![CDATA[The work of the Cross was so significant and we reap so many benefits thanks to Jesus Christ. I take a look at some of those blessings in my lastest devotional.]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/05/blessings-from-the-cross</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/05/blessings-from-the-cross</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt; The work of the Cross was so significant and we reap so many benefits thanks to Jesus Christ. I take a look at some of those blessings in my lastest devotional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-are-we-blessed-because-of-the-cross&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#why-are-we-blessed-because-of-the-cross&quot; aria-label=&quot;why are we blessed because of the cross permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Why are we blessed because of the cross?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have peace with God&lt;/strong&gt; - this is through Justificiation. Justification is when we are declared righteous before a Holy God. This is an act of God only. This is not something that any man or woman can earn. It is only possible thanks to the work of the cross. If Jesus didn’t die on the cross and ressurect we would still be in our sins and could never have peace with God. See 1 Corinthians 15:14&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have access to God&lt;/strong&gt; - in verse 2 it says we access to God. We are no longer seprated from God because of our sin. We can now come to God through Jesus Christ who intercedes for us. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We rejoice in the hope of God&lt;/strong&gt; - in verse 3 we are told that we rejoice in the hope of God. This is a reference to the hope of Heaven. That one day we will be together with the Lord. Jesus is preparing a place for us. (See John 14:2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can rejoice in our trials&lt;/strong&gt; - in verse 4 and 5 we are told that yes even in trials we can rejoice. We can rejoice in trials because we know God is building us up and making us stronger. We need to remember that sometimes trials come into our life to draw us closer to God. So hang in there and know that Jesus is with you through every storm and to be of good cheer because He conquered the world!(John 16:33). Finally when God delivers you out of that storm you will be giving an opportunity to magnify Christ. So rejoice my brothers and sisters in Christ! Rejoice!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The love of God is poured out on our heart&lt;/strong&gt; - God’s love has been poured out on us through the Holy Spirit. How do we know God loves us? In verse 5 we are told that God poured out his love through the Holy Spirit. The Holy Spirit is a gife He gave us. A gift we didn’t deserve. A gift we can never earn. God gave His only begotten son for us. For a righteous person one would not die for but Jesus died for us sinners, for the ungodly, for the unrighteousness. If God gave His only son for us what wouldn’t he give us(Romans 8:32). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are saved from the wrath of God&lt;/strong&gt; - In verse 9 we are told since we are justified by the blood of Christ we are now spared from the wrath of God. Jesus took the wrath of God for our sin by dying on the cross. We escaped judgement thanks to Jesus!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have joy in God&lt;/strong&gt; -  In verse 10 we are told we can have the joy of the Lord because we now have reconciliation with God because of Jesus dying for our sin. Since we now have justification we now have fellowship with God again. Isn’t that such a great blessing. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justification is such a great blessing to us. It really changes our live and gives us so much peace. The blessings of justification are available to ALL believers that are in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; We are justified by the work of the cross. When justified we have the peace of God, we have fellowship with God, we have the Joy of God and most importantly we have the love of God. How great is that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord it is by the work of the cross we have all these amazing blessings. We know this is all posssible thanks to Jesus Christ. We know these blessings are not something we can ever earn. These blessings come from the love you pour out to us through your Holy Spirit. We are so blessed that you shed your wrath on us sinners thanks to Jesus Christ. We are very grateful for your love and your blessings. We are grateful to be justified through the blood of Jesus. It’s in Jesus Holy name we pray. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[God's solution to anxiety]]></title><description><![CDATA[According to the Anxiety and Depression Association of America (ADAA), 40 million American adults are affected by anxiety. That's around 18% of the population. Wow! Some of us try different ways to deal with their anxiety. Some turn to medicine. Some turn to alcohol. None of these are the answer. Jesus is the only answer.]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/cure-for-anxiety</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/cure-for-anxiety</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;According to the Anxiety and Depression Association of America (ADAA), 40 million American adults are affected by anxiety. That’s around 18% of the population. Wow! Some of us try different ways to deal with their anxiety. Some turn to medicine. Some turn to alcohol. None of these are the answer. Jesus is the only answer. Want to know why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this passage Paul is addressing all his fellow believers. Paul really loved the people of Phillipi and he didn’t want them to be anxious.
So what is anxiety? Anxiety is a feeling of worry. It’s a feeling of unease. A feeling of constant thinking and worrying about things that we ourselves can’t control. We all have gone through anxiety at times in life. Some of us may be going through it right now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anxiety is the work of the enemy. The enemey wants us to worry because when we worry we can’t do anything to further the kingdom of God. So what are we to do as Christians? We are to meditate on God’s word and pray. Phillipians 4 is a perfect outline on how we are to deal with anxiety. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this time of panademic a lot of people are worrying. Some are worrying will they have a job? Will they be able to provide food for their family? These are all valid concerns. However, God doesn’t want us to worry. Someone once said worry is a conversation you have with yourself about things you can’t change on your own. While prayer is a conversation with God who can change things. So the big takeaway here is to stay faithful. Let’s take a look at the scripture now and see how God wants us to deal with anxiety. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-have-gods-presence-verse-5&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#we-have-gods-presence-verse-5&quot; aria-label=&quot;we have gods presence verse 5 permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We have God’s presence (Verse 5)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 5 Pauls says the Lord is at hand. What does he mean by that?
He is saying that we have Gods presence.
Since we have God’s presence we should do the following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We should stand fast in the Lord.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We should be of the same mind. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We should always rejoice in the Lord.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When God’s presence is alive in our heart we have joy and His peace. When we are of the same mind we can get along with others more. God will help you to love others, forgive them and get along with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes its hard to feel God’s prescence. We may rush through everything in our laundry list. However, we need to slow down. When we slow we can see God in every situation. When we see God in every situation we can rest in His promises and know that He has a plan for us and we don’t need to worry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gods-peace-verse-7&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#gods-peace-verse-7&quot; aria-label=&quot;gods peace verse 7 permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;God’s peace (Verse 7)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 7 Paul says that we have the peace of God. We have the peace of the God through the Holy Spirit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Spirit guard and protects our minds.
I love his choice of words. When I heard guard It makes me think of a big battle. So God is protecting us in a war we are going through.
It’s true our mind and heart are under constant attack by the enemy. So God is on our side working to protect our emotions and our thoughts.
So always remember we have the peace of God. See John 14:27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-does-the-peace-come-to-us&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-does-the-peace-come-to-us&quot; aria-label=&quot;how does the peace come to us permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;How does the peace come to us?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to pray correctly - we are to pray about everything. Not just big things but small things as well. Prayer is so powerful. So if you want peace make your requests known to God. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is 4 ways to pray. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We need to pray with adoration&lt;/strong&gt; - simply tell God how great he is. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We need to pray with appreciation&lt;/strong&gt; - tell God what you are grateful for. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We need to pray with supplication&lt;/strong&gt; - when we pray to God with supplication we are asking God for His help. When we ask for Gods’ help always come humbly. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We need to pray with petition.&lt;/strong&gt; - this is when we pray to God for a specific need. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prayer is so important because God wants us not to be anxious and instead come to Him with our worries. See 1 Peter 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-have-gods-power-verse-13&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#we-have-gods-power-verse-13&quot; aria-label=&quot;we have gods power verse 13 permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We have God’s power (Verse 13)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 13 which is my favorite bible Paul tells us we have the strength of God. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we are in Christ we have the power of the Holy Spirit helping us. So we can do all things through Christ. Not just some things but ALL things through Jesus Christ. God is our helper. God enables us and gives us strength.When you have God’s power you can be content with any situation in life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people take this verse and take it out of context. Paul is not saying you can jump from one building to another building because you have Christ on your side. He is saying this in regards to what God is calling you to do.  You can succeed in your ministry. You can overcome spiritual warfare. You can be a Godly dad. You can be a Godly husband. Think about it. We have the same strength that raised Christ from the grave on our side!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-have-gods-provision-verse-19&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#we-have-gods-provision-verse-19&quot; aria-label=&quot;we have gods provision verse 19 permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We have God’s provision (Verse 19)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 19 Paul mentions that God has promised to provide for us from the riches of God’s glory. We all know God’s glory is unmeasurable. We also know that God has given up his only begotten son for us(John 3:16). So what won’t he give to us? Jesus once said that He has come so we can have an abundant life in Him (John 10:10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DL Moody called verse 19. God’s blank check.
How great is that? To think about having a blank check from God.
So when worry comes try to relax and think about the promises God has given us. He wants us to have an abundant life and He will provide for it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To recap so why should we not worry?
We shouldn’t worry because we have Gods prescence, His peace, His power and His provision. That is more than anything else we will ever need in life!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gracious Father you are a gracious father indeed! It’s because of your grace that we can have the peace. It’s by your grace we are saved from a life without hope. Saved from a life filled with anxiety. You don’t want us to worry instead you want us to cast our fears and worries at your feet. Your love is so amazing Lord it overflows surely. Thank you for being such an amazing father to us. Than you for giving us your presence so freely. Thank you for the peace you can bring even in the craziest storms. Thank you for the power you supply to all your children. You enable us and you protect our hearts and minds. Most importantly you provide for your children through your riches and grace everyday. Help us to stand in your word and your promises and keep us strong so we can withstand the enemy with your help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its in the wonderful powerful name of Jesus that we pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How God transforms your life through salvation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Being saved is the greatest moment if your life. It's when you are declared righteous before a Holy God. How great is that!! Ever wonder what happens to your life after making that great decision.]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/phases-of-salvation</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/phases-of-salvation</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Being saved is the greatest moment if your life. It’s when you are declared righteous before a Holy God. How great is that!! Ever wonder what happens to your life after making that great decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This passage in Phillipians shows us the plan that God has for our life. Paul wrote this message to address some of the false teachers. These false teachers were called dogs because they did not have a pure mind. They were not in Christ. They were telling the people of Phillipi that they were to still make animal sacrifices to God for forgiveness of sins. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why Paul warns to be aware of dogs and evildoers. These people thought that they can save themselves by their own acts. Which, we know is not true. It is by God’s grace and God’s grace only that we achieve salvation. It is not based on a man’s works (Ephesians 2:8).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just think about it. Even if we could earn salvation by our works. Our most holy acts are like dirty rags before a Holy God. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;justification&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#justification&quot; aria-label=&quot;justification permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Justification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul mentions he wants to be found in Christ. When he says he wants to be found in Christ. He is referring to his salvation and the act of being declared righteous by a holy God. It is important to remember when God saves us we are declared righteous before Him. Only God can declare us, the believing sinner, righteous based on the finished work of Jesus Christ on the cross(Romans 4:25). This process is called justification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justification is to not be confused with God making us righteousness. That is a work in progress until we eventually meet the Lord. It’s God positionally declaring us as righteous before Him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sanctification&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sanctification&quot; aria-label=&quot;sanctification permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sanctification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next phase of salvation is called sanctification.
Sanctification is the process of the Holy Spirit working in us to make us more like Jesus day by day. Jesus loves us and want us to live life more abundantly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul’s goal was to know Christ. He didn’t want to just be in him.
He wanted to know him personally. To know him intimately.
He wanted the power of Christ in his life.
He wanted to the power to turn away from sin.
He wanted to know Christ painfully.
He wanted to know what it was like to suffer for the glory of God. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 12 Paul is indicating that he wants to forget his old self and instead pursue Christ like an athlete pursues a gold medal or trophy (Hebrews 12:1-2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can think of sanctificaiton to the likeness of running a marathon race. We are running to get to the finish line. In our salvation the finish line is when we get to meet Christ. That is our reward.
We also have the pleasure of having Christ help us the entire race.
It’s like having Jesus waiting for you a you at the end of each lap to enourage and inspire you. He is there giving you some water. Patting you on your back and encouraging you along the entire way. That is what sanctification is like. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does God help you through the process of sanctification?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bible&lt;/strong&gt; - God will help you by teaching you through His word. See John 17:17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prayer&lt;/strong&gt; - God will prompt us to pray for help to be more like Jesus. See 1 Timothy 4:4-5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suffering and trials&lt;/strong&gt; - God will sometimes bring trials into our lives because our faith needs to be tried. You can’t trust in a faith that hasn’t been tested. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn’t it great that God wants to help us to be more like Christ. Christ is our savior and we should be hungry to want to be more like Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;glorification&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#glorification&quot; aria-label=&quot;glorification permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Glorification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the final phase of our salvation. This is when we will go to heaven one day when we will really get to know Christ. How will we get to know Christ? We will get to know Christ because our body will become like Christ. This is when we will recieve our glorified body. See 1 Corinthians 15:53-55.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are the three stages of salvation. Isn’t salvation such a great gift. Not only is it great but it’s free. A pouring out of God’s heart and the love He has for us. That he gave His only begotten son. So we can be saved! So we can be set free from the penalty of sin. All God asks is that we believe in His beloved Son. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the way, the truth and the life. No one comes to the father except through Christ. Do you know Jesus? Do you really know him and have a personal relationship with Him? If not now is the time. The time to get right with Christ. To get free from sin. To become a new creation in Christ. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bible says if you hear Jesus knocking its time to let Him into your heart. Now is the time of acceptance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are ready to make that leap of faith. I am very happy for you. That decision will change your life drastically for the good. Now repeat after me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus I know I am a sinner and there is only one way to be forgiven for my sins. It is to put my faith and trust in you. I believe you were born of the virgin Mary and lived a sinless life. That you took my place and died on the cross for my sin. I belive that you ressurected from the dead three days later and that you are exhalted and seated at the right hand of the Father. I want to turn away from my sin and follow you. Please come into my heart and be my Lord. In Jesus Holy name I pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Easter Hope]]></title><description><![CDATA[He has risen! He has risen indeed! Those words bring so much joy to a christians heart. When jesus ressurected from the dead He brought so much hope to the world. ]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/easter-hope</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/easter-hope</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;He has risen! He has risen indeed! Those words bring so much joy to a christians’ heart. When Jesus ressurected from the dead He brought so much hope to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ressurection is the basis of the Christian faith. Without the ressurection we have no hope. We have no chance of Heaven. We are forever in bondage to sin. Non believers to this day try to deny the work of the cross and the fact the Jesus rose from the dead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The passage here in Matthew 28 has clear proof that Jesus rose from the dead. It recounts the story of what happend when Mary Magadlene went to the tomb to see the body of Jesus.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we know Jesus was crucified on Friday and was buried the same day.
So the following day it was a very somber day. People were devastated they thought their savior was truly dead. So you can imagine the suprise Mary was in store for. When she arrived to the tomb she found that the stone was rolled away! The tomb was empty!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One can think why the stone was moved away. Well it wasn’t for Jesus but it had been moved so Mary and the disciples could come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Mary went inside she found there was two angels inside. One was at the foot and one at the head of where Jesus body once was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s go over what we learn from the angels message. The angels message can be broken into three points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fear-not&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fear-not&quot; aria-label=&quot;fear not permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Fear not&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t need to fear because Jesus is alive!!!
Jesus was not there. He was not in the tomb. He had risen like He said He would. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the conclusion of what I believe to be the three greatest events in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The incarnation&lt;/strong&gt; - Jesus was God in flesh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The crucification&lt;/strong&gt; - Jesus died in subsitution for us. He paid His own body for our sins. So we can be freed from sin’s penalty. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ressurection&lt;/strong&gt; - The basis of the Christian fatih. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-we-know-jesus-rose-from-the-dead&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-do-we-know-jesus-rose-from-the-dead&quot; aria-label=&quot;how do we know jesus rose from the dead permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;How do we know Jesus rose from the dead.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus told us He would rise. It was written throughout the bible about His ressurection. We know the bible is all true. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tomb was empty. Jesus physically raised from the dead. It wasn’t just a spiritual awakening but it was a physically awakening. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus was seen alive for 40 days and 40 nights by His apostles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He helped convert Saul&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lives Jesus is changing today. We all have our testimony how Jesus has changed us. We all have become new creations in Christ.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;come-see&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#come-see&quot; aria-label=&quot;come see permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Come see&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come see where the Lord lay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can have His pardon&lt;/strong&gt;. If christ hasn’t risen we are not free from our sins. 1 Corinthians 15:17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have His power&lt;/strong&gt;. Ephesians 1:19-20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have His purpsose&lt;/strong&gt;. God give us a purpose. 1 Corinthians 15:19 Life is vanity without God. Our soul is restless without God. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have His presence&lt;/strong&gt;. Hebrews 13:5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have His pattern&lt;/strong&gt; 1 Corinthians 15:20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have his promise&lt;/strong&gt; - John 14 Jesus will come again for us. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-tell&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#go-tell&quot; aria-label=&quot;go tell permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Go tell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The angels told Mary to tell the apostles the good news that Jesus is alive! That Jesus has conquered sin and death. This is what Jesus wanted. For everyone to know the good news. So we just like Mary should go and tell others. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what we should put our hope in. Telling others about Christ. Giving others the hope that Christ has given you. We can’t put our hope in the government or our jobs. We definitely can’t put our hope in our good works. We don’t go to heaven based on our good works (Ephesians 2:8). There is only one person we can put our hope in and that is Jesus Christ!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your brother in Christ,
&lt;br /&gt; Craig&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Gracious Father you are our one true living hope. You are our father. A father who we can always put our faith in. We thank you for giving up your only begotten son. Who paid the ultimate price for our sins. Just so we can have a future so we can have a hope of going to heaven one day. Thank you so much Lord. Our prayer is to always remember what you did for us and that we never need to live in fear because of the hope you give us. In the mighty wonderful powerful name of Jesus. We pray!
&lt;p&gt;Amen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What a child of God follows]]></title><description><![CDATA[A man of God should be known for what they do and not what they don't do anymore.]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/What-a-child-of-God-follows</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/What-a-child-of-God-follows</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A child of God should be known for what they do and not what they don’t do anymore. Most christians when they give their testimony they sometimes spend too much time talking about what God has stopped them from doing. It is okay to say what you no longer do but your focus should be on talking about what you now do in your life because of God. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-a-child-of-god-should-do&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-a-child-of-god-should-do&quot; aria-label=&quot;what a child of god should do permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What a child of God should do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They should purse righteousness in all they do.&lt;/strong&gt; - What does this look like? It means you should always seek to do what is right. Regardless of where you are or who you are with. This holds true when you are out in your neighborhood, at work, or anywhere in public. God is calling us to be good witnesses. We can’t be good witnesses when we don’t see what is right. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Matthew 6:33&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and all these things will be added to you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They should purse Godliness&lt;/strong&gt; - What does this look like? It means you should have a genuine blameless character. A person that is the same person whether they are in public or private. A person that would do the right thing even when nobody is looking. You are simply seeking God. You can’t pursuse Godliness without pursuing the Holy Spirit. In verse 6(1 Timothy 6:6) we are told Godliness with contentment should be our goal. The Lord is all we need!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They should pursue faith&lt;/strong&gt; - What does this look like? It starts with having a saving faith. This is the faith you have when you accept Jesus Christ as your savior. Saving faith only take a little faith. It’s the sustaining faith you need. This is the faith you have in God when you are going through major trials in your life. This is the kind of faith Peter had when he stepped out of the boat and walked on the water to Jesus (Matthew 14:22-33). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They should pursue love in all they do.&lt;/strong&gt; - What does this look like? We should be loving others like we love ourself. We should be loving others like Jesus loves us. How can we love someone. One way is by serving them. Think about Jesus and how he served his apostles on His last day before dying for us(John 13:1-17). He truly set the example for us. What kind of love should we have? The love that only comes from the Holy Spirt. This love is called Agape love. It is a sacrificial love. It is a kind of love that only believers in Christ can show. Finally who shoud we love? We should love everyone. Our neighbors and even our enemies. Jesus still loved Judas even though he had betrayed Him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;right&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;John 13:35&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“By this all people will know that you are my disciples, if you have love for one another”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They should pursue patience and endurance&lt;/strong&gt; - What does this look like? This means that we wait on the Lord in all we do. That we understand that God’s will will be done and not ours. That everything happens on God’s timing not ours. So what are we to do? We need to be still and know that I am God(Psalms 46:10). We need to never lose faith and stand strong in any opposition we face. Always remembering that trials make us stronger (Romans 5:1-5). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They should pursue meekness&lt;/strong&gt;  - What does this look like? This means we demonstrate power under control. This means we are in control of our flesh. We don’t lose patience. We don’t get easily angered. We become like Jesus. Jesus only mad when God was dishonored (1 Peter 2:21-23). Being meek may be one of the hardest thing to do as a christian. As we need to be in control over our flesh. There is only one way we can do that. We need the help of the Holy Spirit. So make sure to be in good fellowship with God and seeking His help everyday and every minute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in a fallen world. A world that has turned away from God. A world that lacks hope. This is a time more than ever that we need a revival. This is a time where the world needs more children of God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your brother in Christ,
&lt;br /&gt; Craig&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Prayer&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heavenly father we want to thank you that you have given us the opportunity to be children of God. We have this thanks to Jesus! Jesus payed the ultimate sacrifice for us when He died on the cross for us. Jesus paid a debt He didn’t owe and we are forever grateful for the work of the cross. We know you saved us for a reason and that reason is for us to do good works, to spread your gospel and be the salt and light for the world. Lord help to encourage us day by day to walk in the spirit in all we do. Our prayer is for your Holy Spirit to pour into us and your word to pour out of us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mighty powerful wonderful name of Jesus.
Amen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[God's sustaining grace can overcome anything in life]]></title><description><![CDATA[It's by God's grace we are given the amazing gift of salvation. Sometimes we connect his grace only with salvation. However, His grace is much deeper than salvation only. God's grace can sustain us through any storm in life.]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/Gods-sustaining-grace</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/Gods-sustaining-grace</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It’s by God’s grace we are given the amazing gift of salvation. Sometimes we connect his grace only with salvation. However, His grace is much deeper than salvation only. God’s grace can sustain us through any storm in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favorite passages of scripture. Paul wrote this letter to the people of Corinth. He wrote this letter to address the false teachers that were questioning his authority. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He broke his message into two sections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;paul-boasts-about-his-vision-of-paradise-v1-6&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#paul-boasts-about-his-vision-of-paradise-v1-6&quot; aria-label=&quot;paul boasts about his vision of paradise v1 6 permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Paul boasts about his vision of paradise. v1-6&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to defened himself Paul had to boast about himself. Paul was a great man of integrity. A very humbled man. That truly defined what it is like to deny yourself and take up your cross. Boasting for him went against all his beliefs. It was the last thing he  wanted to do. However, in this scenario he didn’t have a choice. So what did he do? He boasted about his weakness instead. He boasted humbly. As he didn’t want the spotlight on him. This is why he said I know a man in Christ in verse 12 (2 Corinthians 12:2). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you had a vison of heaven. You would most likely be running to everyone you know to tell them about it. In this day of time there are many people that claimed they went to heaven and came back. One thing to question are they really telling the truth or just looking to put the spotlight on them. Paul was the complete opposite. He always wanted the spotlight on Christ and he did that by not boasting about his vision of heaven until it was needed as a defense against the false teachers in Corinth.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pauls-painful-experience-v-7-10&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#pauls-painful-experience-v-7-10&quot; aria-label=&quot;pauls painful experience v 7 10 permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Paul’s painful experience v 7-10&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul had a thorn in his flesh. Many people have done a lot of studies about what Paul could have meant by the thorn? The bible does not tell us. SO every study done are just speculations on what it could have been. Since he said his flesh some beieve it ha something to do with his body. It could have been an earache, headache, eye trouble etc. Other’s believe that his thorn could have been a reference to the fallen nature of the world and maybe it was a temptation. Your guess is as good as mine. We do know that it was a trial in his life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul responded to this trial in three ways&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He prayed&lt;/strong&gt; - when a time of difficulty comes we should turn to God in prayer. How should we pray? We can pray like Paul did asking God to take away his thorn. To take away his suffering. Or we can pray for help through that thorn. In that sense we are praying for God’s will to be done not ours. When we pray for God’s will to be done the main thing should seek from God is discernment(James 1:5).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He acknowledged that the thorn was allowed by God&lt;/strong&gt; - Paul says in verse 7 that the thorn in his flesh was given to him by God. So Paul accepted that this was in God’s will for him. So when you have a trial in life think about it like Paul’s thorn. What does God wants you to learn from this thorn? In Paul’s situation it was to keep him from becoming proud. It was also preventive to keep him from sinnning. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He focused on the spiritual gain&lt;/strong&gt; -
What was the spirtual blessings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The thorn forced Paul to keep turning to prayer. Which, brought him closer to God. Key thing to remember is that God’s want us on our knees (2 Chronicles 7:14)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It kept Paul humble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It allowed God to use him. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It taught Paul that God’s grace is sufficient. We are not only saved by God’s grace but we are also sustained by Gods grace. It’s by God’s sustaining grace that we get through any trial in life. How do we allow God’s sustaining grace to work in our lifes? We need to be weak. It’s when we are weak. God’s strength is made perfect. Remember this always. It is okay to be weak. Right now our nation feel weaks. There is not much we can do to stop the coronavirus. It is all in God’s control and that is when His true glory and grace can shine. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your brother in Christ,
&lt;br /&gt; Craig&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Lord we thank you for this amazing scripture. Help us to be like Paul and remember that you are with us through any trial in life. Help us to be humble and turn to you. Help us to acknowledge that it is your will we want done in our lifes and not us. You want to use us and we can make that happen by believing in Christ and always turning to you in prayer. In the mighty powerful name of Jesus. 
&lt;p&gt;Amen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Do not let your heart be troubled]]></title><description><![CDATA[There is so much grief going on with the world right now due to COVID 19.You may feel totally helpless. It is normal to have these feelings. As we can't do anything on our own about it. We need God. God is our refuge and strength.So remember that and don't let your heart be troubled. ]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/do-not-let-your-heart-be-troubled</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/04/do-not-let-your-heart-be-troubled</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There is so much grief going on with the world right now due to COVID 19.You may feel totally helpless. It is normal to have these feelings.
As we can’t do anything on our own about it. We need God. God is our refuge and strength.So remember that and don’t let your heart be troubled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an amazing passage of scripture.
Lets think about the context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happens right after Jesus had finished washing all His disciples feet.
He had just told his disciples that one of His apostles would betray Him.
Naturally all the apostles were worried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that Jesus also just told them that He would only be with them a little longer. Why was this? This was because Jesus was going to go to Heaven to be with the Father and that apostles couldn’t immediatley follow Him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter responded by saying “Lord, why can I not follow You now? I will lay down my life for Your sake.”That was when Jesus said that Peter would deny Him three times before Jesus left them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind Peter was their leader. If peter would deny Christ what would the other apostles do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apostles clearly needed encouragement.That is why Jesus responded with this glorious passage. He didn’t want their hearts to be troubled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/media/posts/do-not-be-troubled.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-our-hearts-not-be-troubled&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#why-should-our-hearts-not-be-troubled&quot; aria-label=&quot;why should our hearts not be troubled permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Why should our hearts not be troubled?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-believe-in-god&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#we-believe-in-god&quot; aria-label=&quot;we believe in god permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We believe in God.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we have Jesus on our side. We get to the Father through the Son. Most importantly God is on the throne and is always in control. Try to remember this and be still keep and keep our faith. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-have-a-home-in-heaven&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#we-have-a-home-in-heaven&quot; aria-label=&quot;we have a home in heaven permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We have a home in Heaven&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus reminds us we have a home in Heaven. This is our real home and we will go there one day. This current world we live is in temporary. So don’t be so bothered on what is going on this world. Instead keep your eyes and mind fixed on heaven and we could overcome our troubles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;god-promised-to-come-back-for-us&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#god-promised-to-come-back-for-us&quot; aria-label=&quot;god promised to come back for us permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;God promised to come back for us&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a promise from God that He will come back and recieve us.
What did Jesus promise? He promised that He will come back for His people. The Church. This is a direct reference to the rapture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says that no man comes to the Father but through me. What did He mean by that? This is great essential doctrine. That the only way to heaven is through Jesus. You must put your trust in Jesus as your savior. He died for your sins.
So that you can have a life in Heaven with Him. How great is that!
Jesus is the way, the truth and the the life. Oh how glorious that statement is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your brother in Christ,
&lt;br /&gt; Craig&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Lord we thank you for this beautiful promise you give us.
Not just this promise but the many promises you give us.
You give us so much hope and a clear blueprint on why we should not let our hearts to be troubled.
Help us to remember this everyday and to put it into practice.
It&apos;s in the Holy mighty name of Jesus that we pray.
&lt;p&gt;Amen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Joy in a divided world]]></title><description><![CDATA[Joy is not dependent on outward things.  Joy comes from inward things when you have rest in your soul. Joy comes from having one mind. A mind that is like Jesus Christ.  in control. This passage give us the blueprint on how to remain joyous]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/03/joy-in-a-divided-world</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/03/joy-in-a-divided-world</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Joy is not dependent on outward things.
Joy comes from inward things when you have rest in your soul.
Joy comes from having one mind. A mind that is like Jesus Christ. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul wrote this letter to the people of Phillipi because there was division among the people. Paul wanted them and us to have unity. The way to unity is to live in humility. Verse 5 is the key to this scripture.
Jesus Christ set the example for us (Phillipians 2:7).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have unity we need to have love(v2), humility(v3) and put others first(v4).
Consider yourself equal with everyone else. Remember we all for short of the glory of God(Romans 3:23).
What does it mean to be humbled? It doesn’t mean not to care about yourself or think any lower about yourself. It simply means to put others first. To think about their needs. How can you serve them. Mark 10:45 and Luke 22:27. You can never be too humble. If you think you are humble. You are not. Humble has no pride at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;paul-pleads-with-us-for-humility&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#paul-pleads-with-us-for-humility&quot; aria-label=&quot;paul pleads with us for humility permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Paul pleads with us for humility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 1-4 paul pleads with us to be humble. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;paul-gives-the-pattern-of-humility&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#paul-gives-the-pattern-of-humility&quot; aria-label=&quot;paul gives the pattern of humility permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Paul gives the pattern of humility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christ set the pattern for us. He completely humbled himself for us.
This is why We need to have the same mindset of Jesus to humble ourselves for others.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In verse 6 Paul points out that Jesus is God. That Jesus is soverign and that Jesus was God.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In verse 7 Paul tells us how Jesus went from a soverign God to a humble servant just for us.
He emptied Himself. He laid aside His majesty and took on humanity/humility. He took off his Crown and became a peasant. He did this voluntarily and for us. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 8 Pauls tell us that Christ humbled himself for us. He gave himself up for us. He died and sacrificied Himself for us. Why did Jesus die on the cross for us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To give us Salvation(John 3:16). By his death we were given the opportunity to be rescued from the penalty of sin(Romans 6:23).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He died on the cross so he can defeat sin and Satan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He died so the love of God could be revealed to us. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;paul-reveals-the-power-for-humility&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#paul-reveals-the-power-for-humility&quot; aria-label=&quot;paul reveals the power for humility permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Paul reveals the power for humility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Finally in verse 12 Paul concludes to say that we need to work out our own salvation with fear and trembling. What did Paul mean by this? He was simply saying we need to go out and live our salvation. It doesn’t mean we are to work for our salvation. Remember we can never earn our salvation. It is a free gift given to us(Ephesians 2:8). It means we are working for the good of the church because of our salvation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  We are to let God work in us(v13). Our goal is to be like Jesus through sanctification. God uses trials to help and shape us to be more like Jesus. So when trials come your way. Don’t pray to God to be delivered from that trial. Instead pray for revelation on what God wants you to learn from that trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  We need to shine (v14:16) - It is our duties as children of God to be a good witness. We should always show joy to others and not to complain. When we shine our light we will be given opportunities to tell us others about Jesus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Why should we shine our light? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  So we can rejoice in the day of Christ. One day we will be caught up in the air to meet Jesus Christ. What a glorious day that will be. To think one day we will sit in the reward seat of Christ too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  This is what Paul focused on. He had a heavenly mindset and knew the race he was running was not in vain. That all his labor was not for nothing. He knew one day he would hear “Well done, good and faithful servant” (Matthew 25:23). Wouldn’t that bring you so much joy? It sure brings me joy just to think about when that day comes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord we just want to thank you that we can remain joyous through any circumstance in life. Lord you set the example for us on how to live.
My prayer is that we can be of one mind, united in all we do and that we will be inspired that our work for your kingdom is never in vain!
In the wonderful and powerful name of Jesus I pray!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your brother in Christ,
Craig&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Joy in any Circumstance]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sometimes it may be hard to remain joyous under intense situations like what we are going through with the Corona Virus. However, it's important to remember that God is in control. This passage give us the blueprint on how to remain joyous]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/03/joy-in-any-circumstance</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/03/joy-in-any-circumstance</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it may be hard to remain joyous under intense situations like what we are going through with the Corona Virus. However, it’s important to remember that God is in control. The passage here in Philippians 1 give us the blueprint on how to remain joyous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phillipians 1 we know was written by Paul while he was in prison (Philippians 1:13-14). Paul loved the Phillipians and he wrote this message to encourage his fellow believers. Paul was very thankful to have fellowship with the people of Phillipi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-things-that-paul-was-thankful-for-in-spite-of-his-circumstances&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#three-things-that-paul-was-thankful-for-in-spite-of-his-circumstances&quot; aria-label=&quot;three things that paul was thankful for in spite of his circumstances permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Three things that Paul was thankful for in spite of his circumstances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-fellowship-in-the-gospel&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1-fellowship-in-the-gospel&quot; aria-label=&quot;1 fellowship in the gospel permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;1. Fellowship in the Gospel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   Despite what is going on we have fellowship with others. We may be limited to our homes right now but we have many means to stay in fellowship with others via social media. It’s times like this were we should be eager to fellowship more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-opportunities-to-spread-the-gospel&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2-opportunities-to-spread-the-gospel&quot; aria-label=&quot;2 opportunities to spread the gospel permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;2. Opportunities to spread the Gospel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  His current circumstances gave opportunity to further the spread of the gospel even more. Paul was placed in jail, shipwrecked and even bit by a snake. Paul didn’t let that stop him from his goal of having Christ preached. Instead of being overwhelmed by his trials he used it as platform to further the gospel. Paul had the mindset that no matter what happens in life He was still going to preach Christ. So yes Paul was able to rejoice even in extreme circumstances and so can we if keep that mindset!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-christ-will-be-magnified-through-him&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3-christ-will-be-magnified-through-him&quot; aria-label=&quot;3 christ will be magnified through him permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;3. Christ will be magnified through Him&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  We want Christ to be magnified in all we do. When we rejoice, which is the theme of the book Phillipians, under any circumstance like Paul did we allow others to see Christ through us. This should motivate us to remain joyous and to bear fruit so we can be good witnesses to all. We are here for a purpose and we should keep that in mind in these hard times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do remain joyful? Prayer is so important. We need to be praying to God for help and praying for our fellow believers. Which is exactly what Paul did for his fellow brothers and sistes in Christ in Phillipi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Paul pray for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He prayed that the believers would have an abounding love in verse 9. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He prayed that the believers would have a discerning approval of execellent things. Priortizing what is most valuable and most important. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He prayed that his fellow believers would have a genuine and blameless character. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He prayed that his fellow believers would bear fruit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul was convinced everything that happened to him was part of Gods will so he was able to remain joyous. As long as others can see Christ in you. You are bearing fruit. To bear fruit furthers the kingdom and this will bring you joy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has begun the good work in us and He will complete it. We were justified and now we are being sanctified. Finally we will be glorified one day when we are in Heaven with Jesus. That is why we can rejoice when Paul says to live is Christ and to die is gain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly we have the opporunity to share and defend the gospel through any circumstance in life when we keep the same mindset Paul had. God bless you all and Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your brother in Christ,
Craig&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to my site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello guest! Welcome to my Site]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/03/welcome-to-my-site</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/03/welcome-to-my-site</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class=&quot;post-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/romans1-16.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello guest and welcome to my site.
My mission is simple. To spread the good news about Jesus Christ. It is our role as Christians and children of God. God has been putting it on my heart to use my technical skills to help further his kingdom. So I have gone and put together this site to proclaim the goodness of God. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a completely new experience for me so I welcome your feedback. I will be adding new features over time. With the end goal being the same. My hope is to share the good news of Christ and to help plant the seed in any unbeliever’s heart. while at the same time helping to edify my current brothers and sisters in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My site will consist of mostly devotionals from sermons I hear at my church and other sources like the radio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to know more about myself and my testimony you can visit my &lt;a href=&quot;https://thevictoryisyours.com/pages/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;about me&lt;/a&gt; page. As far as my beliefs you can check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://thevictoryisyours.com/pages/my-beliefs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;my belief’s page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going through challenging times right now with the Corona Virus.  Now is the time to be the light of the world.
It is our duty as christians to bring hope to the world!(Matthew 5:14-16). &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Three years in Christ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Three years it has been! Three years I have been set free. Three years I am no longer a slave to sin. Three glorious years it has been. Three years I have been blessed by God's overflowing mercy and grace when He saved a sinner like me.]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/03/three-years-in-christ</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/03/three-years-in-christ</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class=&quot;post-image post-image--inline-images&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/inchrist.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Water Baptism&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/inchrist2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three years it has been! Three years I have been set free. Three years I am no longer a slave to sin. Three glorious years it has been. Three years I have been blessed by God’s overflowing mercy and grace when He saved a sinner like me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t seem to stop thinking about how blessed I am. To be justified before a Holy God. To have the gift of the Holy Spirit helping me everyday. To be able to meet my Lord and Savior Jesus Christ one day. I get giddy just thinking about it. Yes there has been many highs but there has also been many trials. I would be lying if I told you that life has been a breeze for me the past three years. In the last year I found out my daughter was diagnosed with Cerebral Palsy and my mom with Alzheimier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receiving that kind of news can cripple someone. However, God didn’t let that happen to me. He didn’t give us a spirt of fear but a spirit of power and of a sound mind. That is why I am so grateful to be a child of God. Without the help of the Holy Spirit. I really would have been lost navigating through the difficult times. He has been there everyday for us. From counseling and encouraging us through every single therapy session for Avery to making tough decisions such as pulling my mother out of her home and moving her into a care facility. I know one thing for sure God has never let me down and no words can ever describe the feeling of being a child of God.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What to do when life falls apart]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Corona Virus has caused many to fear. Some to question if the world is really falling apart. Do you feel this way? How do you respond?Some will turn to social media. Which, could cause you to panic. Some may turn to drugs. Some may turn to alcohol. Some may even consider suicide. What should we really do? Turn to God. He is your refuge and your strength!]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/02/what-to-do-when-life-falls-apart</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/02/what-to-do-when-life-falls-apart</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Corona Virus has caused many to fear. Some to question if the world is really falling apart. Do you feel this way? How do you respond? Some will turn to social media. Which, could cause you to panic. Some may turn to drugs. Some may turn to alcohol. Some may even consider suicide. What should we really do? Turn to God. He is your refuge and your strength!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-should-run-to-god&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#we-should-run-to-god&quot; aria-label=&quot;we should run to god permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We should run to God.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should we run to God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is our refuge. Jeremiah 16:19 and Psalm 46:1. When we turn to God we have His protection. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is our strength. Proverbs 18:10. When we turn to God He give us strength to overcome anything in life. Phillipians 4:13 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is our help. When you believe in God you receieve the Holy Spirit who is your helper (Acts 2:38). The Holy Spirit is the best help we can recieve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God takes away our fear. God is always with us so no need to fear. Deuteronomy 31:8 and Jeremiah 1:8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;drink-of-the-lord&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#drink-of-the-lord&quot; aria-label=&quot;drink of the lord permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Drink of the Lord&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should be thirsty for what the Lord has to offer (John 4:13-14). We can think of Jesus like a river. He is overflowing and His love is never ending. He is the living water and if we drink of Him we will no longer be thirsty for things in our flesh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We receive joy. Psalm 46:4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We receive stability. Psalm 46:5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We receive help from the Holy Spirit. Psalm 46:5 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-still-and-know-god-8-12&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#be-still-and-know-god-8-12&quot; aria-label=&quot;be still and know god 8 12 permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Be still and know God (8-12).&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has a plan for you. So its best to be patient and trust in His plan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In psalm 46:8 we are told that the Lord ceases wars. This could be prothetic to His second coming. When Jesus will put and end to the great tribulation. What this shows is that God really cares for you. So cast your cares on Him and He will give you rest(Matthew 11:28).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God wants you to not just tell him about your problems but to also leave them with Him. Simply lay your problems at the feet of God. When you let God take care of your problems. It will build up your faith and testimony and most importantly God’s glory can shine through anything. Yes God is bigger than the Corona Virus. We will overcome this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the most important part is that we can’t run to God unless He is our savior. Do you know Christ personally? Is He your Lord and Savior? If not now is the time(Revelation 3:20) to know Him and trust Him as your Lord.
&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Godly walk]]></title><description><![CDATA[Psalm 1 is a great passage that shows the difference of a Godly walk vs a non Godly walk]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/01/the-godly-walk</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/01/the-godly-walk</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We need to be separate from the world but not isolated from the world. We should not walk in the counsel of the wicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;who are the wicked? They are the unbelievers. They are the atheists. They are people who don’t seek God. They are sinners who rebel against God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;remember we all are sinners and we all for short of the glory of God. We need God’s help to not sin. The Holy Spirit works to convict us of sin day by day through the process of sanctification. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sin usually starts small. It usually starts with us walking in Sin. Then next we know we are standing in it. Which, leads to us sitting in sin. We can’t forget the progression of sin. James 1:14-15 tell us &lt;blockquote&gt;14 But each one is tempted when he is drawn away by his own desires and enticed. 15 Then, when desire has conceived, it gives birth to sin; and sin, when it is full-grown, brings forth death.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sin leads to sadness while holiness leads to happiness. This is why we should be saturated in God’s word. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-is-what-should-do-daily&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#here-is-what-should-do-daily&quot; aria-label=&quot;here is what should do daily permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Here is what should do daily&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the Bible &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delight in the Word or God. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditate day and night on the Bible. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We should obey the word of God - James 1:22-25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does mediation mean? Means to empty your mind. If you ever visit Israel you may see the Jewish people muttering words non stop. They are in turn actually meditating on God’s word. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-the-benefits-of-being-a-man-of-god&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-are-the-benefits-of-being-a-man-of-god&quot; aria-label=&quot;what are the benefits of being a man of god permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What are the benefits of being a man of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We become like a tree. We have a purpose. We were planted by God. We will bear fruit through any season in life. We should prosper in all we do.
&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trust God and Don't worry]]></title><description><![CDATA[Trust is a hard thing to do for some people. When you worry you are not trusting God. God loves you and wants you to trust in him. Will you?]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/01/trusting-god-and-not-worrying</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/01/trusting-god-and-not-worrying</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;   &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is hard thing to do for some people. When you worry you are not trusting God. God loves you and wants you to trust in him. Will you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust begins with being a believer. Do you believe in Jesus Christ? If you do that means you have already put your faith in Jesus Christ. So you have established a relationship of trust in Him as your lord. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard part is to keep that trust in all seasons of your life. In life you will go through many trials. However, be of good cheer because your Lord has conquered the world. (John 16:33)  Trials come into our life to build up our faith and trust. Trials bring you closer to God. How do you become closer? It starts by trusting in God. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has a plan for you. He has promised this to us in Jeremiah 29:11. He has great plans for us. For us to have a future with Him.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get it sometimes its hard to have trust when you can’t see every step of the way. However, always remember as a fellow Christian. We walk by faith(2 Corinthians 5:7) and not by sight. Walking by faith requires us to be praying constantly (1 Thessalonians 5:17-18). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let our prayers be known to God. Do not worry about anything. Instead pray about everything and make your requests be known to God (Philippians 4:6). The peace of God surpasses all understanding and will guard your heart and mind. So relax and don’t worry and let God control. This is His will for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Happiness is a Choice]]></title><description><![CDATA[Would you believe me if I told you that happiness is a choice? I strongly believe this is true and here is why]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/01/happiness-is-a-choice</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/01/happiness-is-a-choice</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Being happy is all about perspective. Yes you can choose happiness. Happiness is a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are some people just not happy? Well once reason is as a world we have a tendency to focus on the things we don’t have. Instead we should be grateful for the things we do have. Remember everything good in your life comes from God (James 1:17). So it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has a different will for all of us so its up to Him how and when He blesses us. Again happiness comes down to perspective. Once you change your perspective you will see how blessed you really are. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally remember it’s always best to be humble. God resists the proud and gives grace to the humble.                           &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[We can have Victory with Jesus Christ]]></title><description><![CDATA[The passage of Matthew 4 is one of the greatest inspirational messages. It's a clear example of how we can overcome any trial in life.]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/01/we-can-have-victory-with-christ</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/2020/01/we-can-have-victory-with-christ</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The passage of Matthew 4 is one of the greatest inspirational messages. It’s a clear example of how we can overcome any trial in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we do this? The easiest answer is to keep your eyes on Jesus. Think about what happend to Peter when he took his eyes off Jesus. The minute he started to look at the waves he began to drown. This is a classic example of what happens when we take our eyes off Jesus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said &lt;blockquote&gt;
“These things I have spoken to you, that in Me you may have peace. In the world you [f]will have tribulation; but be of good cheer, I have overcome the world.” - John 16:33 &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the most important thing to remember. Our Lord and Savior Jesus Chrsit overame sin and death!! There is nothing Jesus can’t overcome and we have Jesus on our side. How great is that!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this passage of scripture Jesus sets the exmaple on how to deal with temptation. Jesus is tempted three times by Satan in the desert. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Jesus respond? He responds by using the Sword of the Spirit. This is the most important weapon we need to defeat the enemy. It is our offensive and our defense as well. When we use the Sword of the Spirit we don’t feel victim to the lifes of the enemy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its very important to remember our enemy the devil prowls around like a roaring lion looking for someone to devour(1 Peter 5:8). He is very manipulative. That is why it’s so important to know the word of God. Look at how in verse 6 Satan actually tried to twist the truth and use it against Jesus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus responded and said it is written you should not temp the Lord your God. By knowing and using the Word of God as a weapon. The enemy can’t condemn us because we have the truth. The Word of God! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember what it says in Romans 8:1.
&lt;q&gt;There is therefore now no condemnation to them which are in Christ Jesus, who walk not after the flesh, but after the Spirit.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we remember this we can and will have victory over the enemey and just about anything else. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>