<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Victory in Jesus]]></title><description><![CDATA[We can have victory because Our Lord and Savior conquered Sin and Death!]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com/</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 21:28:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Joy in a divided world]]></title><description><![CDATA[Joy is not dependent on outward things.  Joy comes from inward things when you have rest in your soul. Joy comes from having one mind. A mind that is like Jesus Christ.  in control. This passage give us the blueprint on how to remain joyous]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/joy-in-a-divided-world</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/joy-in-a-divided-world</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Joy is not dependent on outward things.
Joy comes from inward things when you have rest in your soul.
Joy comes from having one mind. A mind that is like Jesus Christ. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul wrote this letter to the people of Phillipi because there was division among the people. Paul wanted them and us to have unity. The way to unity is to live in humility. Verse 5 is the key to this scripture.
Jesus Christ set the example for us (Phillipians 2:7).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have unity we need to have love(v2), humility(v3) and put others first(v4).
Consider yourself equal with everyone else. Remember we all for short of the glory of God(Romans 3:23).
What does it mean to be humbled? It doesn’t mean not to care about yourself or think any lower about yourself. It simply means to put others first. To think about their needs. How can you serve them. Mark 10:45 and Luke 22:27. You can never be too humble. If you think you are humble. You are not. Humble has no pride at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;paul-pleads-with-us-for-humility&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#paul-pleads-with-us-for-humility&quot; aria-label=&quot;paul pleads with us for humility permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Paul pleads with us for humility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 1-4 paul pleads with us to be humble. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;paul-gives-the-pattern-of-humility&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#paul-gives-the-pattern-of-humility&quot; aria-label=&quot;paul gives the pattern of humility permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Paul gives the pattern of humility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christ set the pattern for us. He completely humbled himself for us.
This is why We need to have the same mindset of Jesus to humble ourselves for others.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In verse 6 Paul points out that Jesus is God. That Jesus is soverign and that Jesus was God.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In verse 7 Paul tells us how Jesus went from a soverign God to a humble servant just for us.
He emptied Himself. He laid aside His majesty and took on humanity/humility. He took off his Crown and became a peasant. He did this voluntarily and for us. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 8 Pauls tell us that Christ humbled himself for us. He gave himself up for us. He died and sacrificied Himself for us. Why did Jesus die on the cross for us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To give us Salvation(John 3:16). By his death we were given the opportunity to be rescued from the penalty of sin(Romans 6:23).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He died on the cross so he can defeat sin and Satan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He died so the love of God could be revealed to us. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;paul-reveals-the-power-for-humility&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#paul-reveals-the-power-for-humility&quot; aria-label=&quot;paul reveals the power for humility permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Paul reveals the power for humility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Finally in verse 12 Paul concludes to say that we need to work out our own salvation with fear and trembling. What did Paul mean by this? He was simply saying we need to go out and live our salvation. It doesn’t mean we are to work for our salvation. Remember we can never earn our salvation. It is a free gift given to us(Ephesians 2:8). It means we are working for the good of the church because of our salvation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  We are to let God work in us(v13). Our goal is to be like Jesus through sanctification. God uses trials to help and shape us to be more like Jesus. So when trials come your way. Don’t pray to God to be delivered from that trial. Instead pray for revelation on what God wants you to learn from that trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  We need to shine (v14:16) - It is our duties as children of God to be a good witness. We should always show joy to others and not to complain. When we shine our light we will be given opportunities to tell us others about Jesus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Why should we shine our light? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  So we can rejoice in the day of Christ. One day we will be caught up in the air to meet Jesus Christ. What a glorious day that will be. To think one day we will sit in the reward seat of Christ too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  This is what Paul focused on. He had a heavenly mindset and knew the race he was running was not in vain. That all his labor was not for nothing. He knew one day he would hear “Well done, good and faithful servant” (Matthew 25:23). Wouldn’t that bring you so much joy? It sure brings me joy just to think about when that day comes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord we just want to thank you that we can remain joyous through any circumstance in life. Lord you set the example for us on how to live.
My prayer is that we can be of one mind, united in all we do and that we will be inspired that our work for your kingdom is never in vain!
In the wonderful and powerful name of Jesus I pray!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your brother in Christ,
Craig&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Joy in any Circumstance]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sometimes it may be hard to remain joyous under intense situations like what we are going through with the Corona Virus. However, it's important to remember that God is in control. This passage give us the blueprint on how to remain joyous]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/joy-in-any-circumstance</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/joy-in-any-circumstance</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 23:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it may be hard to remain joyous under intense situations like what we are going through with the Corona Virus. However, it’s important to remember that God is in control. The passage here in Philippians 1 give us the blueprint on how to remain joyous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phillipians 1 we know was written by Paul while he was in prison (Philippians 1:13-14). Paul loved the Phillipians and he wrote this message to encourage his fellow believers. Paul was very thankful to have fellowship with the people of Phillipi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-things-that-paul-was-thankful-for-in-spite-of-his-circumstances&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#three-things-that-paul-was-thankful-for-in-spite-of-his-circumstances&quot; aria-label=&quot;three things that paul was thankful for in spite of his circumstances permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Three things that Paul was thankful for in spite of his circumstances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-fellowship-in-the-gospel&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1-fellowship-in-the-gospel&quot; aria-label=&quot;1 fellowship in the gospel permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;1. Fellowship in the Gospel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   Despite what is going on we have fellowship with others. We may be limited to our homes right now but we have many means to stay in fellowship with others via social media. It’s times like this were we should be eager to fellowship more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-opportunities-to-spread-the-gospel&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2-opportunities-to-spread-the-gospel&quot; aria-label=&quot;2 opportunities to spread the gospel permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;2. Opportunities to spread the Gospel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  His current circumstances gave opportunity to further the spread of the gospel even more. Paul was placed in jail, shipwrecked and even bit by a snake. Paul didn’t let that stop him from his goal of having Christ preached. Instead of being overwhelmed by his trials he used it as platform to further the gospel. Paul had the mindset that no matter what happens in life He was still going to preach Christ. So yes Paul was able to rejoice even in extreme circumstances and so can we if keep that mindset!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-christ-will-be-magnified-through-him&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3-christ-will-be-magnified-through-him&quot; aria-label=&quot;3 christ will be magnified through him permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;3. Christ will be magnified through Him&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  We want Christ to be magnified in all we do. When we rejoice, which is the theme of the book Phillipians, under any circumstance like Paul did we allow others to see Christ through us. This should motivate us to remain joyous and to bear fruit so we can be good witnesses to all. We are here for a purpose and we should keep that in mind in these hard times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do remain joyful? Prayer is so important. We need to be praying to God for help and praying for our fellow believers. Which is exactly what Paul did for his fellow brothers and sistes in Christ in Phillipi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Paul pray for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He prayed that the believers would have an abounding love in verse 9. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He prayed that the believers would have a discerning approval of execellent things. Priortizing what is most valuable and most important. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He prayed that his fellow believers would have a genuine and blameless character. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He prayed that his fellow believers would bear fruit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul was convinced everything that happened to him was part of Gods will so he was able to remain joyous. As long as others can see Christ in you. You are bearing fruit. To bear fruit furthers the kingdom and this will bring you joy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has begun the good work in us and He will complete it. We were justified and now we are being sanctified. Finally we will be glorified one day when we are in Heaven with Jesus. That is why we can rejoice when Paul says to live is Christ and to die is gain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly we have the opporunity to share and defend the gospel through any circumstance in life when we keep the same mindset Paul had. God bless you all and Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your brother in Christ,
Craig&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to my site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello guest! Welcome to my Site]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/welcome-to-my-site</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/welcome-to-my-site</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class=&quot;post-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/romans1-16.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello guest and welcome to my site.
My mission is simple. To spread the good news about Jesus Christ. It is our role as Christians and children of God. God has been putting it on my heart to use my technical skills to help further his kingdom. So I have gone and put together this site to proclaim the goodness of God. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a completely new experience for me so I welcome your feedback. I will be adding new features over time. With the end goal being the same. My hope is to share the good news of Christ and to help plant the seed in any unbeliever’s heart. while at the same time helping to edify my current brothers and sisters in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My site will consist of mostly devotionals from sermons I hear at my church and other sources like the radio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to know more about myself and my testimony you can visit my &lt;a href=&quot;https://thevictoryisyours.com/pages/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;about me&lt;/a&gt; page. As far as my beliefs you can check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://thevictoryisyours.com/pages/my-beliefs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;my belief’s page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going through challenging times right now with the Corona Virus.  Now is the time to be the light of the world.
It is our duty as christians to bring hope to the world!(Matthew 5:14-16). &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Three years in Christ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Three years it has been! Three years I have been set free. Three years I am no longer a slave to sin. Three glorious years it has been. Three years I have been blessed by God's overflowing mercy and grace when He saved a sinner like me.]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/three-years-in-christ</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/three-years-in-christ</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class=&quot;post-image post-image--inline-images&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/inchrist.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Water Baptism&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/inchrist2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three years it has been! Three years I have been set free. Three years I am no longer a slave to sin. Three glorious years it has been. Three years I have been blessed by God’s overflowing mercy and grace when He saved a sinner like me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t seem to stop thinking about how blessed I am. To be justified before a Holy God. To have the gift of the Holy Spirit helping me everyday. To be able to meet my Lord and Savior Jesus Christ one day. I get giddy just thinking about it. Yes there has been many highs but there has also been many trials. I would be lying if I told you that life has been a breeze for me the past three years. In the last year I found out my daughter was diagnosed with Cerebral Palsy and my mom with Alzheimier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receiving that kind of news can cripple someone. However, God didn’t let that happen to me. He didn’t give us a spirt of fear but a spirit of power and of a sound mind. That is why I am so grateful to be a child of God. Without the help of the Holy Spirit. I really would have been lost navigating through the difficult times. He has been there everyday for us. From counseling and encouraging us through every single therapy session for Avery to making tough decisions such as pulling my mother out of her home and moving her into a care facility. I know one thing for sure God has never let me down and no words can ever describe the feeling of being a child of God.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What to do when life falls apart]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Corona Virus has caused many to fear. Some to question if the world is really falling apart. Do you feel this way? How do you respond?Some will turn to social media. Which, could cause you to panic. Some may turn to drugs. Some may turn to alcohol. Some may even consider suicide. What should we really do? Turn to God. He is your refuge and your strength!]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/what-to-do-when-life-falls-apart</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/what-to-do-when-life-falls-apart</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The Corona Virus has caused many to fear. Some to question if the world is really falling apart. Do you feel this way? How do you respond? Some will turn to social media. Which, could cause you to panic. Some may turn to drugs. Some may turn to alcohol. Some may even consider suicide. What should we really do? Turn to God. He is your refuge and your strength!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-should-run-to-god&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#we-should-run-to-god&quot; aria-label=&quot;we should run to god permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We should run to God.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should we run to God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is our refuge. Jeremiah 16:19 and Psalm 46:1. When we turn to God we have His protection. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is our strength. Proverbs 18:10. When we turn to God He give us strength to overcome anything in life. Phillipians 4:13 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is our help. When you believe in God you receieve the Holy Spirit who is your helper (Acts 2:38). The Holy Spirit is the best help we can recieve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God takes away our fear. God is always with us so no need to fear. Deuteronomy 31:8 and Jeremiah 1:8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;drink-of-the-lord&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#drink-of-the-lord&quot; aria-label=&quot;drink of the lord permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Drink of the Lord&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should be thirsty for what the Lord has to offer (John 4:13-14). We can think of Jesus like a river. He is overflowing and His love is never ending. He is the living water and if we drink of Him we will no longer be thirsty for things in our flesh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We receive joy. Psalm 46:4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We receive stability. Psalm 46:5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We receive help from the Holy Spirit. Psalm 46:5 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-still-and-know-god-8-12&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#be-still-and-know-god-8-12&quot; aria-label=&quot;be still and know god 8 12 permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Be still and know God (8-12).&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord has a plan for you. So its best to be patient and trust in His plan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In psalm 46:8 we are told that the Lord ceases wars. This could be prothetic to His second coming. When Jesus will put and end to the great tribulation. What this shows is that God really cares for you. So cast your cares on Him and He will give you rest(Matthew 11:28).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God wants you to not just tell him about your problems but to also leave them with Him. Simply lay your problems at the feet of God. When you let God take care of your problems. It will build up your faith and testimony and most importantly God’s glory can shine through anything. Yes God is bigger than the Corona Virus. We will overcome this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the most important part is that we can’t run to God unless He is our savior. Do you know Christ personally? Is He your Lord and Savior? If not now is the time(Revelation 3:20) to know Him and trust Him as your Lord. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Godly walk]]></title><description><![CDATA[Psalm 1 is a great passage that shows the difference of a Godly walk vs a non Godly walk]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/the-godly-walk</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/the-godly-walk</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We need to be separate from the world but not isolated from the world. We should not walk in the counsel of the wicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are the wicked? They are the unbelievers. They are the atheists. They are people who don’t seek God. They are sinners who rebel against God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember we all are sinners and we all for short of the glory of God. We need God’s help to not sin. The Holy Spirit works to convict us of sin day by day through the process of sanctification. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sin usually starts small. It usually starts with us walking in Sin. Then next we know we are standing in it. Which, leads to us sitting in sin. We can’t forget the progression of sin. James 1:14-15 tell us &lt;blockquote&gt;14 But each one is tempted when he is drawn away by his own desires and enticed. 15 Then, when desire has conceived, it gives birth to sin; and sin, when it is full-grown, brings forth death.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sin leads to sadness while holiness leads to happiness. This is why we should be saturated in God’s word. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-is-what-should-do-daily&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#here-is-what-should-do-daily&quot; aria-label=&quot;here is what should do daily permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Here is what should do daily&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the Bible &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delight in the Word or God. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditate day and night on the Bible. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We should obey the word of God - James 1:22-25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does mediation mean? Means to empty your mind. If you ever visit Israel you may see the Jewish people muttering words non stop. They are in turn actually meditating on God’s word. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-the-benefits-of-being-a-man-of-god&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-are-the-benefits-of-being-a-man-of-god&quot; aria-label=&quot;what are the benefits of being a man of god permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What are the benefits of being a man of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We become like a tree. We have a purpose. We were planted by God. We will bear fruit through any season in life. We should prosper in all we do. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trust God and Don't worry]]></title><description><![CDATA[Trust is a hard thing to do for some people. When you worry you are not trusting God. God loves you and wants you to trust in him. Will you?]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/trusting-god-and-not-worrying</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/trusting-god-and-not-worrying</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Trust is hard thing to do for some people. When you worry you are not trusting God. God loves you and wants you to trust in him. Will you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust begins with being a believer. Do you believe in Jesus Christ? If you do that means you have already put your faith in Jesus Christ. So you have established a relationship of trust in Him as your lord. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard part is to keep that trust in all seasons of your life. In life you will go through many trials. However, be of good cheer because your Lord has conquered the world. (John 16:33)  Trials come into our life to build up our faith and trust. Trials bring you closer to God. How do you become closer? It starts by trusting in God. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has a plan for you. He has promised this to us in Jeremiah 29:11. He has great plans for us. For us to have a future with Him.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get it sometimes its hard to have trust when you can’t see every step of the way. However, always remember as a fellow Christian. We walk by faith(2 Corinthians 5:7) and not by sight. Walking by faith requires us to be praying constantly (1 Thessalonians 5:17-18). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let our prayers be known to God. Do not worry about anything. Instead pray about everything and make your requests be known to God (Philippians 4:6). The peace of God surpasses all understanding and will guard your heart and mind. So relax and don’t worry and let God control. This is His will for you.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Happiness is a Choice]]></title><description><![CDATA[Would you believe me if I told you that happiness is a choice? I strongly believe this is true and here is why]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/happiness-is-a-choice</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/happiness-is-a-choice</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Being happy is all about perspective. Yes you can choose happiness. Happiness is a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are some people just not happy? Well once reason is as a world we have a tendency to focus on the things we don’t have. Instead we should be grateful for the things we do have. Remember everything good in your life comes from God (James 1:17). So it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has a different will for all of us so its up to Him how and when He blesses us. Again happiness comes down to perspective. Once you change your perspective you will see how blessed you really are. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally remember it’s always best to be humble. God resists the proud and gives grace to the humble.                           &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[We can have Victory with Jesus Christ]]></title><description><![CDATA[The passage of Matthew 4 is one of the greatest inspirational messages. It's a clear example of how we can overcome any trial in life.]]></description><link>https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/we-can-have-victory-with-christ</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thevictoryisyours.com//posts/we-can-have-victory-with-christ</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The passage of Matthew 4 is one of the greatest inspirational messages. It’s a clear example of how we can overcome any trial in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we do this? The easiest answer is to keep your eyes on Jesus. Think about what happend to Peter when he took his eyes off Jesus. The minute he started to look at the waves he began to drown. This is a classic example of what happens when we take our eyes off Jesus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said &lt;blockquote&gt;
“These things I have spoken to you, that in Me you may have peace. In the world you [f]will have tribulation; but be of good cheer, I have overcome the world.” - John 16:33 &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the most important thing to remember. Our Lord and Savior Jesus Chrsit overame sin and death!! There is nothing Jesus can’t overcome and we have Jesus on our side. How great is that!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this passage of scripture Jesus sets the exmaple on how to deal with temptation. Jesus is tempted three times by Satan in the desert. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Jesus respond? He responds by using the Sword of the Spirit. This is the most important weapon we need to defeat the enemy. It is our offensive and our defense as well. When we use the Sword of the Spirit we don’t feel victim to the lifes of the enemy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its very important to remember our enemy the devil prowls around like a roaring lion looking for someone to devour(1 Peter 5:8). He is very manipulative. That is why it’s so important to know the word of God. Look at how in verse 6 Satan actually tried to twist the truth and use it against Jesus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus responded and said it is written you should not temp the Lord your God. By knowing and using the Word of God as a weapon. The enemy can’t condemn us because we have the truth. The Word of God! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember what it says in Romans 8:1.
&lt;q&gt;There is therefore now no condemnation to them which are in Christ Jesus, who walk not after the flesh, but after the Spirit.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we remember this we can and will have victory over the enemey and just about anything else. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>